girlheartfood.com 2019-12-28

# Privacy Policy & Terms of Use - Girl Heart Food

**PRIVACY POLICY AND TERMS OF USE (POLICIES)**

Last Updated:  March 21, 2019

Girl Heart Food (“Website”) is governed by the following Privacy Policy and Terms of Use.

This Privacy Policy and Terms of Use (aka Policies) sets out how Girl Heart Food or girlheartfood.com (“Website”) uses and protects any information that you give while using [https://girlheartfood.com](https://girlheartfood.com/).

We take your privacy seriously.  Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this Website, you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this Privacy Policy and Terms of Use.

The purpose of this Privacy Policy and Terms of Use is to inform you of what information we may collect and how it may be used as well as the Terms of Use while using this Website.

 **CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND TERMS OF USE**

Girl Heart Food may change this Privacy Policy and Terms of Use from time to time by updating this page.  You should check back periodically to ensure you are happy with any changes made to this Privacy Policy and Terms of Use.

 **CONSENT**

By using our Website, you hereby consent to our Privacy Policy and Terms of Use. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy and Terms of Use, please do not use this Website. Your continued use of the Website following the posting of changes to this Privacy Policy and Terms of Use will be deemed acceptance of these changes.

 **DISCLAIMER**

Views & opinions expressed on girlheartfood.com are those of the blogger and are just that, views & opinions.  They are from the personal experience of the blogger at girlheartfood.com. I cook for my own enjoyment and entertainment.  I’m not a professional cook/chef/baker/dietitian/nutritionist/medical expert or offering any kind of professional advice. Following any advice provided on this Website is at your own risk. Under no circumstances will I be held liable for any loss or damage arising from the use of this Website.  No warranty implied.  I make no representation as to the accuracy or completeness of any information found on this Website, including the information contained in the outbound links (websites) I point you to. Users/readers should verify any information regarding products/services & the like themselves should they wish.

 **INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

 **Information you Voluntarily Provide**

We collect personal information when you submit your name, email address and any other information to us on this Website. Examples include:

  * When you subscribe to our newsletter
  * When you e-mail us
  * When you comment on this site
  * When you fill out a contact form on this site

 **Information We Collect From Others:**

We may receive information about you from other sources.  For instance, if you use a third party service provider through the site, they may transfer information to us for fulfillment.

 **Automatically Collected Information**

Like many websites, girlheartfood.com and our service providers use cookies, web beacons and other technologies to receive and store certain types of information when you interact with us through your computer, table or mobile device.  Using these technologies helps us recognize you, customize your experience and make relevant marketing messages.  Some of the types of information we collect are:

  *  **Log Files**

Like many websites, girlheartfood.com uses information from log data which may include information such as the Internet Protocol (IP) address of a visitor’s computer, as well as the browser type, browser version, the pages of this site that have been viewed by the visitor, the time and date of the visit, the time spent on those pagers and other statistics.  While this data is used to track visitors’ behavior, it is not linked to any information that allows this Website to personally identify the visitor.

  *  **Cookies**

Cookies are very small text files that are stored on your computer when you visit some websites. Like many websites, girlheartfood.com uses cookies to collect information and track visitor behaviour. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences. This helps us analyze data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes.

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not.

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. The method of doing so can vary from browser to browser and from version to version.  You can, however, obtain up-to-date information about blocking and deleting cookies via these links:

(a) <https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en> (Chrome);

(b) <https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences> (Firefox);

(c) [http://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/cookies/](https://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/cookies/) (Opera);

(d) <https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies> (Internet Explorer);

(e) https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411 (Safari); and

(f) [https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows–10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy ](https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy)(Edge).

If you decline cookies in your browser, please note, this may result in all functions on this website not working properly.  For more information about cookies, you can visit <https://www.aboutcookies.org/>.

  *  **Analytic Services**

This Website also uses Google Analytics, which collects, monitors and analyzes usage data of visitors to help this Website understand how visitors are using the Website. User data is anonymous.  Users can completely block Google Analytics tracking by using Google’s [opt-out browser add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/). Furthermore, Google has their own [privacy policy.](https://privacy.google.com/)

 **HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION**

We may use the information collected in the following ways:

  * To operate and maintain the Website.
  * To send you promotional information, such as newsletters. Each e-mail promotion will provide information on how to opt-out of future mailings.
  * To send you administrative communications, such as administrative emails, confirmation emails, technical notices, updates on policies, or security alerts.
  * To respond to your comments or inquiries.
  * To provide you with user support.
  * To track and measure advertising on the Website.
  * To protect, investigate, and deter against unauthorized or illegal activity.
  * We also may use your information to manage our business or perform functions as otherwise described to you at the time of collection.

Please note, we use both personally identifiable information and non-personally identifiable information, and combinations of both types, as described above.

 **SHARING AND DISCLOSURE**

We do not share your personal information with others except as indicated within this Privacy Policy and Terms or Use or when we inform you and give you an opportunity to opt out of having your personal information shared.

Additionally, the Website may use third-party service providers to service various aspects of the Website. Each third-party service provider’s use of your personal information is dictated by their respective privacy policies. We do not authorize them to use or disclose your personal information except in connection with providing their services. These service providers may have access to your personal information or other information in order to provide these functions.  In addition, some of the information we request may be collected by third party providers on our behalf.  This Website currently uses the following third-party service providers.

 **Google Analytics**  – this third-party service provider tracks Website usage and provides information such as referring websites and user actions on the Website.  This service uses cookies. Google Analytics may capture your IP address, but no other personal information is captured by Google Analytics.  This Website has activated the option to anonymize IP addresses.  We use the information provided by this service provider to better understand our audience, enhance user experience and tailor our content to our readers’ interests.  Users can completely block Google Analytics tracking by using Google’s [opt-out browser add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/). Furthermore, Google has their own [privacy policy.](https://privacy.google.com/)

 **MonsterInsights** – this third-party service provider allows this Website to manage its Google Analytics.  This third-party service provider syncs with Google Analytics.  It tracks Website usage, browser information and may capture your IP address. However, this Website has activated the option to anonymize IP addresses.

 **MailChimp –  **this third-party service provider is used for the delivery of email updates and newsletters.  Your e-mail address is stored for the purposes of delivering such communications.  By subscribing to our newsletter/mailing list, you acknowledge that the information you provide will be transferred to MailChimp for processing in accordance with their [Privacy Policy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/) and [Terms](https://mailchimp.com/legal/terms/).

 **Cloudflare –** this third-party service provider is used for Website optimization and security.  This third-service party service provider may collect user IP addresses, system configuration information, and other information about traffic to and from the Website (“log data”) in order to detect new threats, identify malicious third parties, and provide security protection of the Website.  Their privacy policy effective May 25, 2018 can be found [here](https://www.cloudflare.com/privacypolicy/).

 **Social Pug –** this third-party service provider is used for social sharing buttons so a particular blog post, for example, can be shared via social media should a user wish to do so. When a user presses one of these buttons, his or her social network login is sent to the appropriate network to enable the share to happen.  For example, if a user wants to share a blog post on the Website via Twitter, the login prompt for Twitter will appear so the user can log into his or her Twitter account to share.  Each of these social media networks has their own privacy policy.  Social Pug does not collect, store or distribute user information; even though this is the case, please use your own discretion when providing any login information or sharing to any social network site.

 **Akismet** – this third-party service provider checks user comments  against a global database of spam to prevent this Website from publishing malicious content. Their privacy policy can be found [here](https://automattic.com/privacy/).

 **VaultPress** – this third party service provider backs up this Website and provides security scanning.

 **WPopt** – this third party service provider provides the web hosting for this Website.

Please note, this list may be amended from time to time at the Website’s sold discretion.

Except when required by law, we will not sell, distribute, or reveal your e-mail address or other personal information without your consent.  However, we may disclose or transfer personal information collected through the Website to third parties who acquire all or a portion of our business, which may be the result of a merger, consolidation, or purchase of all or a portion of our assets, or in connection with any bankruptcy or reorganization proceeding brought by or against us.

 **ANONYMOUS DATA**

From time to time, we may use anonymous data, which does not identify you alone or when combined with data from other parties.  This type of anonymous data may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising or other uses. Examples of this anonymous data may include analytics or information collected from cookies.

 **ADVERTISING**

 **Display Ads**

We may use third party advertising companies to serve content and advertisements when you visit this website.  These companies may use cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies to serve you advertisements that may be of interest to you. In doing so, these vendors may collect non-personal data such as your browser type, your operating system, pages visited, time of visit, content viewed, ads viewed, and other clickstream data. The use of cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies by these advertising service vendors is subject to their own privacy policies, not ours.  To learn more about this behavioural advertising practice or to opt out of this type of advertising, you can visit networkadvertising.org.

 **Retargeting Ads**

This website may engage with third party companies such as Facebook, Google or Instagram in an effort to market the Website. These third party companies use cookies to serve ads based on a user’s past visits to the Website.

Opt out of Facebook retargeting Ads [here](https://www.facebook.com/help/568137493302217).

Opt out of Google retargeting ads [here](https://adssettings.google.com/anonymous?sig=ACi0TChTvVmgqnbrjSVgpkqDtXoKDXFnRlxYskRgu4mu8FxuGeegs7lXV8xEkcRzSEhBO0YXb6oeF5MKO6d9c0IVgRdMXoEq6ifkgrreWXrQfTJzOvi6pVM&hl=en).

 **SPONSORED POSTS**

From time to time, this Website may be compensated by brands or companies to feature their products in blog posts.  The relationship will always be disclosed up-front within the blog post. All sponsored content is disclosed in accordance with the FTC’s requirements.  These sponsored posts may utilize tracking pixels (aka web beacons) which may contain cookies to collect data regarding usage and audience.  The information is collected by the sponsoring company or brand to track the results of the sponsored post.  No personally identifiable information collected by this website is used in conjunction with these tracking pixels.

We would never affiliate ourselves with a brand or product that we didn’t enjoy or think would be beneficial to our readers.  Readers are reminded to use their own discretion when deciding if such brand, product is right for them.

 **EMAIL NEWSLETTERS**

This Website has a voluntary newsletter subscription used to inform subscribers about products, services and/or content supplied by this website.  Users can subscribe through an online automated process should they wish, but do so at their own discretion.  Users can also unsubscribe at any time should they wish to do so.

This Website uses MailChimp (a third-party service provider) to send out our email updates and newsletters.  Your email address is stored for purposes of delivering such communications. By subscribing to our newsletter/mailing list, you acknowledge that the information you provide will be transferred to MailChimp for processing in accordance with their [Privacy Policy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/) and [Terms](https://mailchimp.com/legal/terms/).

All newsletters sent to you may contain tracking pixels.  The pixel is embedded in emails and allows analysis of the success of the newsletter.  These pixels may allow us to see if and when you open an email from us and which links (if any) within the email you click.  From this information, we may adapt the content of future newsletters to the interests of the user. If you subscribe to our mailing list, you can unsubscribe at any time.

 **CONTROLLING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information in the following ways:

  * Never submit sensitive information on this website or anything you do not want people to have access to.  If you choose to submit any type of information on this site, it will be subject to these Policies and Terms of Use.
  * If you have previously agreed to us using your personal information for direct marketing purposes, you may change your mind at any time by contacting us.
  * If you are subscribed to our newsletter, you may unsubscribe at any time should you wish to do so by following the unsubscribe links in our emails. Also, you may notify us at [girlheartfood@gmail.com](mailto:girlheartfood@gmail.com)to be removed from our mailing list.
  * You can instruct your browser to accept cookies, to notify you when a cookie is issued or to not receive cookies at any time.
  * You can decide not to use this Website.

 **RIGHTS RELATED TO YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

  * Opt-out – You may opt-out of future e-mail communications by following the unsubscribe links in our e-mails. You may also notify us at [girlheartfood@gmail.com](mailto:girlheartfood@gmail.com)
  * Access – You may access the personal information we have about you by submitting a request to [girlheartfood@gmail.com](mailto:girlheartfood@gmail.com)
  * Amend – You may contact us at [girlheartfood@gmail.com](mailto:girlheartfood@gmail.com)to amend or update your personal information.
  * Forget – In certain situations, you may request that we erase or forget your personal data. To do so, please submit a request to [girlheartfood@gmail.com](mailto:girlheartfood@gmail.com).

Please note that we may need to retain certain information for record- keeping purposes or to complete transactions, or when required by law.

 **COMMENT POLICY**

This Website is a fun website with recipes, chit chat &/or food-related topics.  It is totally awesome when visitors/users make comments which allow for fun, positive interaction.  However, please note that this Website reserves the right to not publish or delete comments which are negative or inappropriate.  Please be kind.

Any comments posted on this Website become the property of this Website and may be used in this blog (Website), e-mails, or products and/promotion of this Website or the Girl Heart Food brand.

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available [here](https://automattic.com/privacy/). After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

Moreover, any comments readers leave on this Website are public and may be read, collected or used by anyone. Your name, website (if applicable) and date/time of comment will be displayed. However, your e-mail address and IP address will be secure.

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

Readers accept these risks when providing personal information and posting comments to this Website.

 **SENSITIVE PERSONAL INFORMATION**

At no time should you submit sensitive personal information to this Website.  This includes your social security number, information regarding race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious belief, health information, criminal background or trade union memberships.  If you elect to submit such information to us, it will be subject to this Privacy Policy and Terms of Use.

 **CHILDREN AND OUR WEBSITE**

Our Website is not directed to children under 16. We do not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 16. If you learn that your child has provided us with personal information without your consent, please contact us at [girlheartfood@gmail.com](mailto:girlheartfood@gmail.com) and we will use our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records.

 **SECURITY**

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. It is important for readers to understand, however, that no method of transmitting information over the internet or electronic storage is 100 percent secure.

 **LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES**

Our Website may contain links to other websites. However, once you have used these links to leave our Website, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website (or outbound link). Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide while visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this Privacy Policy and Terms of Use. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

 **EMBEDDED CONTENT FROM OTHER SITES**

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

 **NUTRITIONAL INFORMATION DISCLOSURE**

I’m not a professional cook/chef/baker/dietitian/nutritionist/medical expert and do not offer any professional medical or nutritional advice.  My recipes should be taken as a guideline only and your best judgement should be used to ensure the food is safety prepared and/or a good fit for your diet.  Please consult a medical professional if you are unsure.

This Website occasionally offers nutritional information for recipes contained on this Website. This information is provided as a courtesy and should be considered an estimate and not be construed as a guarantee of its validity. This information is calculated through an online nutritional calculator. Varying factors such as product types/brands and the way ingredients are processed may change the nutritional information in any given recipe.

 **GIVEAWAY POLICY**

From time to time, this Website may host giveaways. These events may be self-sponsored by the blog owner or may be sponsored by another individual or business. This may or may not be plainly stated in the actual giveaway. If you need further clarification, please e-mail us at girlheartfood@gmail.com.

Unless otherwise stated, all giveaways will follow these guidelines:

  * Winners will be chosen randomly.
  * Are hosted with the intent of adding fun to this Website and in no way are meant to be a form of gambling.
  * Open only to residents of Canada and U.S., unless otherwise stated.
  * Start and end on dates of the giveaway will be listed on each specific contest.
  * If giveaway is self-hosted the prize will be mailed to the winner(s) within 14 days.
  * Please note that this Website chooses the companies that we work with very carefully and only choose companies that we think are reputable and honest. If a giveaway is sponsored by one of these outside companies or businesses, this Website cannot be held liable or responsible, should a vendor choose not to fulfill a promised prize.
  * Once winner is randomly chosen, they will be contacted via the e-mail address they provided upon entering the contest. In order to send the prize to the winner, we may require a mailing address.  Winner recognizes that their information (name, e-mail address and/or mailing address) may need to be passed onto the prize delivering party for fulfillment of the giveaway should the prize be sponsored by an outside entity.
  * We may, at our discretion, make public the first name and province or state of our giveaway winner(s). All other contact information will remain private.
  * Each winner will have 48 hours to claim the prize, after being notified via the e-mail they used to enter the contest. After 48 hours, if there is no response (or winner does not meet entry requirements (as specified when they entered), another winner will be randomly chosen.
  * All giveaway entrants agree to be honest and not cheat the systems; any suspect of fraud is decided upon by this Website and/or the sponsor, and entrants may be disqualified at our discretion.
  * Any prizes that may result in tax liability for the winner(s) are the winner(s) responsibility.
  * We are not responsible for lots or damaged items. Replacement items will not be provided.
  * Giveaways may be promoted on Facebook, Twitter, e-mail or other social network sites. This is a means of promotion only, and any promotion on those sites is not to be interpreted as Facebook or Twitter partaking in, or being in any way responsible for that particular contest.
  * We reserve the right to end, extend, or change a giveaway for any reason and without prior notice.
  * Odds of winning in one of our giveaways depend on the number of entrants.

 **HEADINGS**

The headings for sections on this Website are for convenience only and shall not affect the meaning of the provisions of this Privacy Policy and Terms of Use.

 **COPYRIGHT POLICY**

Unless otherwise noted, all content, photography and video is copyright of this Website.  Please do not reproduce any text, videos or photos without my prior written consent.  If you want to use one of my photos from a recipe for a round-up style post, that is ok.  Ensure you provide a link back (credit) to the original post on this site.  You can email at girlheartfood@gmail.com if you have any further questions.

 **REVISIONS**

The materials appearing on this Website may include technical, typographical, or photographic errors. This Website does not warrant that any of the materials on its Website are accurate, complete, or current. This Website may make changes to the materials contained on its Website at any time without notice. This Website does not, however, make any commitment to update the materials.

 **YOUR ACCEPTANCE  OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND TERMS OF USE (POLICIES)**

This Website may change this Privacy Policy and Terms of Use from time to time by updating this page.  You should check back periodically to ensure you are happy with any changes made to this Privacy Policy and Terms of Use.

By using this Website, you signify your acceptance of this Privacy Policy and Terms of Use.  If you do not agree to this Policy and Terms of Use, please do not use our Website.  Your continued use of the Website following the posting of changes to this Privacy Policy and Terms of Use will be deemed your acceptance of these changes.

 **CONTACT US**

If you have any questions or comments related to this Privacy Policy and Terms of Use, please contact us at Dawn at girlheartfood@gmail.com
